Ivan Grishaev

An IT engineer focused on Python, Clojure & Java.

Tags: Python, Clojure(Script), Java, GraalVM, Postgres, Datomic, AWS Lambda, Kafka, Python, Emacs, LaTeX. Armenia, UTC +4

Links:

- ivan@grishaev.me
- github.com/igrishaev
- linkedin.com/in/igrishaev

Summary

- 8 years of Python: Django & Flask, Fast API, Pytest, Tox;
- 8 years of Clojure: Aleph/Manifold, core.async, Component/Integrant;
- GraalVM + native-image compilation of Java & Clojure projects for AWS Lambda;
- experience with different data sources: PG, Datomic, Kafka, Cassandra, etc.
- some experience with frontend: re-frame, React;
- good with Emacs and LaTeX.

Mentoring

I educated a couple of students and helped them graduate and find their first job. I've been preparing them to the interview. Their diploma projects were considered the best ones across the course. I teach Egnlish, informally.

In the past, I made Python lessons for the educational platform Hexlet.io. Each class consisted of a video course, a quiz and a code task to complete. The video courses are still available on Youtube.

Projects & Open source

I maintain about a dozen of Clojure libraries hosted on Github (see my Clojars profile). One of them is Etaoin which is widely used (700 stars, spotted in many companies).

I wrote a short book in English about Java interop. Get in on Leanpub.

I wrote a full print book in Russian called "Clojure in Production". The book covers web development, Clojure.spec, exception handling, systems, testing and other subjects. It is partially translated to English in my blog.

I wrote the second volume called "Clojure in Production: vol. 2".

Experience

May 2023 — now: Senior Clojure developer @ Vast European Fintech Company

I maintain a complex risk management system in a vast European fintech company. Clojure, Java, AWS, Lambda, Postgres, message queues. Lots of services and distributed computations.

Nov 2022 — Sep 2023: Senior Clojure developer @ Audience Republic (Australia)

I'm working on a vast Clojure code base + Postgres. Some of the things I've done so far:

- $\bullet\,$ introduced Docker & integration tests;
- added linters, improved the CI;
- wrote some internal documentation;
- implemented new business features.

Feb 2022 — Sep 2022: Senior Clojure developer @ Clashapp/Huddles (USA)

I support vast Clojure codebase with plenty of components:

- AWS, Postgres;
- ullet Integration with third-party providers;
- Handling AppStore notifications;
- Massive integration tests.

Dec 2018 — Feb 2022: Senior Clojure developer @ Exoscale (Switzerland)

At Exoscale, I mostly worked on various network orchestrators. We had plenty of data sources like Mysql, Cassandra, Kafka which required precise control. I used Aleph & Manifold stack for my apps. I maintained some legacy apps driven with Core.async.

Exoscale has plenty of internal stuff which I contributed to. One of them is a web framework named Blueprint built on top of Open-API spec and data schemas.

I made an app to transfer vast files (+100Gb) into our infrastructure.

I integrated the web SSH terminal to the admin page (noVNC, JavaScript, Clojure on backend).

I made a lot of improvements to the internal billing system written in Python, Django and Pytest.

I made a draft of the official CLI client for Exoscale API.

During the last year at Exoscale, I worked on DBaaS: a massive feature that integrates a third-party database provider into the Exoscale infrastructure. That involved HTTP API, data processing, reconciliation, billing processing and more.

Jan 2018 — Dec 2018: Senior Clojure developer @ Health Samurai (Russia)

Health Samurai is a startup focused on medical data. They develop FHIR-compatible software, and I was working on several internal services. One of them named US NPI is open source and may be found on GitHub. This service fetches the official US NPI registry and fills the database. It also provides flexible REST API, search capabilities and Swagger UI.

I spent four months working on a mobile app for iOS. The app was driven by Re-Natal and ClojureScript. We managed to pass Apple's review and had the app released in App Store.

2016 — Dec 2017: Clojure developer @ Flyerbee (Switzerland)

Flyerbee is a web app that automates outdooring advertisements. I worked on both server and UI parts using a modified version of the Luminus stack. That included Clojure, Ring, JDBC/PostgreSQL, and Re-frame.

2015 — 2016: Python developer @ SwiftServe (UK)

SwiftServe is a worldwide CDN network that competes with AWS CloudFront. I developed three internal services written in Python and Django and set up micro-service architecture in AWS cloud. I integrated a modern unit-test framework into our pipeline and added a new documentation system.

2013 — 2015: Python developer @ Dataart

DataArt is a vast outsourcing company. The main project I've been working on was a worldwide online game with 70M players. I developed several internal services, set up message queues and wrote lots of unit tests.

2008 — 2013: Various contracting jobs

I've been working on various projects including Python and Delphi. My clients were mostly individuals and small companies. I developed desktop apps, websites and simple Android applications.

Education

Bachelor's Degree at Applied Informatics in Economics, Chita University of Economics, 2003 – 2008

Other

I am a father of three. Enjoy winter activities. Run my blog in both English and Russian.